Theory here:
1. Creating the folder
On terminal:
mkdir OST ( make directory )
cd OST ( change directory )

2. Initialising Git
On terminal:
git init 
Message :-> Initialized empty Git repository in /path/to/OST/.git/
a. .git folder is the brain and heart of the repository- not to be messed with directly.
b. It's the "version control" part of the version control system.
c. This step tells git to start tracking changes in this folder.
d. When one runs git init, Git creates this hidden folder.
e. Inside this folder, Git stores everything it needs to track your project's history:
( all the commits )
 i.The complete history of every change you've ever made.
 ii.Pointers to different branches (more on this later).
 iii.Configuration settings for your repository.

3. Create a Simple File
echo "Theory Here" > Theory.txt

4. git status shows that file has not been tracked yet. 
Git sees the file but does not have it in its history yet.

5. "Stage" the file
gid add Theory.txt

6. git status now shows that the file is being tracked.

7. git commit -m "a meaninful, descriptive and concise message to be written here"
"This is a stable, working version of my code, and I want to be able to come back to it 
whenever I want."
This is like a snapshot in time. Official "save point" in history.
Note: It is important to always commit after add.


8. modified:   Theory.txt is the message that is received when Theory.txt is modified. 
It appears in an orange colour.
THe file stored in disk is different from what is stored in the .git folder

9. Git vs Github
Git is a tool ( a COMMAND LINE PROGRAM FOR version control ) , software that runs on the computer, engine that keeps track of project's history, manages commits and allows user to go back in time.
Local tool. 
Github is the platform : website and service that HOSTS Git repositories. Shared Cloud Storage for Git projects. 

